today i want to talk about how to
retarget on facebook now that the ios
14.5 changes have come through and
there's a lot more changes coming from
apple but they're going to really
restrict marketers but in the past we've
been able to retarget website visitors
on facebook and show ads to them but
what apple has done is they have
basically stopped that from their
devices if someone's on an apple device
they are now able to say look i don't
want facebook to track me so therefore
facebook can't track if they've hit a
certain website as a marketer the
retargeting audiences have shrunk
tremendously now the power that we used
to have has kind of been evaporated away
it still works because there are still
some people out there who are letting
ios track them
with facebook there's also people on
desktops and all of that who hit the
website on a desktop and they're able to
be retargeted so it's not everything
it's just a big chunk but
the problem is retargeting has
diminished there are ways of getting
around it like the facebook conversion
api which has really moved some of that
tracking onto the server as opposed to
the device and so that is good as well
it's not dead but there are other ways
to retarget your prospects on with
facebook ads and that's what i want to
talk about today so stick around and i'm
going to go into a few examples of how
you can still retarget maybe not the
same maybe a bit better maybe not as
good you decide
facebook retargeting how do we do it all
right so website retargeting is not as
good as it used to be but there are two
other ways that i have found that we can
use and the first way is video
retargeting if you put a video on
facebook and show that to your audience
you can now track people well you always
have been able to but this is what you
should be doing now is track people who
watch 3 seconds 10 seconds 15 seconds 25
50 75 95 and 100 of that video whoever
watches that as percentages you can now
retarget those people with an ad now in
the past we used to do this but now
we're relying more on it because the
website retargeting isn't as good
but can i say it's very powerful what i
love about this is you can actually
build a funnel on facebook with no
landing pages with no website required
and so all the tracking no email none of
that so it's very powerful i've been
taking advantage of it i've been seeing
some great results and i know a lot of
my peers in the industry have been doing
the same thing so i want to encourage
you if you've seen your website
retargeting suffer then start putting
videos on facebook and retargeting
people based on how much they watch the
other way of doing it is with a lead
form if you have a lead form on facebook
it means when someone clicks the button
to download your thing
they can actually it opens up a form on
facebook it doesn't go to your website
and that form is pre-filled in with all
their details so their phone number
email and name is pre-filled in and all
they have to do is click a button and
you get all those details it's a really
good way of generating leads but also
it's a good way of retargeting if
someone clicks the ad but doesn't fill
in the form we can re-target them just
like we could on a website and so yes
it's not perfect but it's something you
can do and you should be doing if
retargeting is something that's been
suffering for you you've got video view
audiences that you can create and
retarget and lead form audiences that
you can create and retarget and i want
to encourage you that these two are
legitimate ways of doing it you just
have to figure it out for your business
and try and find a way to make it work
for you so don't complain you know
facebook is changing everything changes
the world continues to change some
things get better some things get worse
but facebook is still extremely powerful
i want to encourage you to move and to
grow
with the changes don't diminish your
spending in your advertising because
you're the only one that's going to
suffer all right if you want to know
more about this you can join my facebook
group where we do lots of training like
this i click the link below or you can
book a call with me and i'd love to chat
with you and see how we could i could
personally help you with your business
so again there'll be a link around where
you can click a button and book a call
have a great day i'll see you on the
next video